Nicholas Podniestrzanski

727-686-8782 | Nickpodski@gmail.com

About Me

Hello, I've been working in video production since 2012. I've done all levels of productions and positions including; Director, Producer, Assistant Director, Production Management, Production Associate, Video Editor, Color Correction, Live Video Editor, Grip, Camera Operator, and various other positions over the years. My biggest moment is Producing/Directing early morning coverage of The Open in 2019.

I've recently started taking a Full Stack Web Developer coding boot camp with UCF, and I will finish the program in June of 2021. I hope to transition my career down that path.

Experience

GOLF CHANNEL, MARCH 2014 - CURRENT

PRODUCER/DIRECTOR

- Directed and produced European Tour Coverage for golf channel. I had a live editor, Audio Operator, Technical director and Talent to host from Orlando. Created our own open and scene set to join live into the world feeds coverage.
 - Audio Cues with our Talent for coming in and out of breaks with important shots that would have been missed in break.
 - Time Slip Management so viewers didn't miss anything important.
 - Produced Live Promos to add into coverage.
- Produced and Directed for PGA Tour, LPGA Tour, Asian Tour, and others including the 2019 early world feed coverage of The Open.

 Produced segments for Primetime, and full shows for PGA Tour Live's feed on Golf Channel's Air.

LIVE EDITOR

- Editing using various platforms including Dreamcatcher, EVS, and Avid to support live shows and tournament coverage.
- Media management of files, recording and routing of live sources, QC and tagging of files for archive. Color Correction, adding graphics and editing short stories to air within shows.
- Live playback of content during shows.
 Time slip of live feeds including; Press conferences, live golf, and live golf for International coverage for added commercial inventory and enhancement of coverage.

ESPN. JUNE 2012 - 2015

- Video editor and live video editor at ESPN Wide World of Sports.
- Proficient with Dyno, Final Cut Pro, and Edius while there.
- Edited a variety of sports and content for them. Other roles include: Assistant Director, Grip Utility, Camera Operator, and Production associate.

FREELANCE EDITOR

VARIOUS COMPANIES, MARCH 2012 – CURRENT

- Edited for ESPN, NBC, ABC, Waterlight Media, Platinum Video, Castaldo Studios, IMG Productions, and other companies.
- Proficient with Avid, Final Cut Pro, and Adobe Premiere Pro for linear Editing.
- Proficient with EVS, Dreamcatcher,
 Dyno, and Simplylive TV for live editing and replay for live productions.

Nicholas Podniestrzanski

727-686-8782 | Nickpodski@gmail.com

Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE | FEBURARY 2012 | FULL SAIL UNIVERSITY

Related coursework: HD Broadcast, Producing, Video Editing, Documentary Filmmaking, Video production, and various industry classes.

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP | JUNE 2021 | UCF

Related coursework: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Node.js, and various other languages and methods.